A Guide to the Department of Conservation and Development, Division of History, Records, 1927-1950
Library of Virginia
- Series II. Virginia War History Project, 1942-1946 (Accession 24806b)
  - Subseries A: Counties
    - Montgomery County, 1942-1946 (See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 2) (Box 76, Folder 12)
    - Nansemond County, 1945-1946 (Box 76, Folder 13)
    - Nelson County, 1942-1945 (Box 76, Folder 14)
    - New Kent County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk County, 1943, 1945-1946 (Box 77, Folder 2)
    - Northampton County, 1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 3)
    - Northumberland County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 4)
    - Nottoway County, 1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 5)
    - Orange County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 (See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 3) (Box 77, Folder 6)
    - Page County, 1943-1946 (Box 77, Folder 7)
    - Patrick County, 1942-1946 (Box 77, Folder 8)
    - Pittsylvania County, 1943-1945 (Box 77, Folder 9)
    - Powhatan County, 1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 10)
    - Prince Edward County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 11)
    - Prince Edward County (Hampden Sydney College), 1942-1944 (Box 77, Folder 12)
    - Prince George County, 1943-1946 (Box 77, Folder 13)
    - Prince William County, 1942-1946 (Box 77, Folder 14)
    - Princess Anne County, 1942-1943 (Box 77, Folder 15)
    - Pulaski County, 1943-1946 (Box 77, Folder 16)
    - Rappahannock County, 1943, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 17)
    - Richmond County, 1943, 1945-1946 (Box 78, Folder 1)
    - Roanoke County, 1945-1946 (Box 78, Folder 2)
    - Rockbridge County, 1942-1946 (Box 78, Folder 3)
    - Rockingham County, 1946 (Box 78, Folder 4)
    - Russell County, 1942-1946 (Box 78, Folder 5)
    - Scott County, 1943-1946 (Box 78, Folder 6)
    - Shenandoah County, 1943, 1945-1946 (Box 78, Folder 7)
    - Smyth County, 1943-1946 (Box 78, Folder 8)
    - Southampton County, 1945-1946 (Box 78, Folder 9)
    - Spotsylvania County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 78, Folder 10)
    - Stafford County, 1942-1945 (Box 78, Folder 11)
    - Surry County, 1943-1946 (Box 78, Folder 12)
    - Sussex County, 1942-1943 (Box 78, Folder 13)
    - Sussex County, 1943 (Box 78, Folder 14)
    - Sussex County, 1943-1944 (Box 79, Folder 1)
    - Tazewell County, 1942-1945 (Box 79, Folder 2)
    - Warren County, 1943, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 3)
    - Warwick County, 1943-1945 (Box 79, Folder 4)
    - Washington County, 1943-1945 (Also includes Abingdon) (Box 79, Folder 5)
    - Westmoreland County, 1942-1943, 1945-1946 (Box 79, Folder 6)
    - Wise County, 1943-1945 (Box 79, Folder 7)
    - Wythe County, 1942-1943, 1945 (Also includes Wytheville) (Box 79, Folder 8)
    - York County, 1943-1946 (Box 79, Folder 9)
  - Subseries B: Cities
    This subseries is housed in 1 box and one oversize box and is arranged alphabetically by city. This subseries consists of incoming correspondence and reports from local correspondents and replies from Division of History staff members. Very few localities submitted any reports. Most of the correspondence concerns the collection of "Personal War Service Record of Virginia's Ward Dead".
    - Alexandria, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 10)
    - Bristol, 1943, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 11)
    - Buena Vista, 1942-1945 (Box 79, Folder 12)
    - Charlottesville, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 13)
    - Clifton Forge, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 14)
    - Danville, 1945-1946 (Box 79, Folder 15)
    - Fredericksburg, 1942-1944 (Box 79, Folder 16)
    - Hampton, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 17)
    - Harrisonburg, 1943, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 18)
    - Lynchburg, 1942-1946 (Box 79, Folder 19)
    - Martinsville, 1945 (Box 79, Folder 20)
    - Newport News, 1942, 1945 (Box 80, Folder 1)
    - Norfolk, 1942-1945 (Box 80, Folder 2)
    - Petersburg, 1942-1943, 1945 (Box 80, Folder 3)
    - Portsmouth, 1942-1946 (Box 80, Folder 4)
    - Richmond, 1942, 1944-1945 (Box 80, Folder 5)
    - Roanoke, 1942, 1945-1946 (Box 80, Folder 6)
    - South Norfolk, 1945 (Box 80, Folder 7)
    - Staunton, 1945-1946 (Box 80, Folder 8)
    - Suffolk, 1943, 1945-1946 (Box 80, Folder 9)
    - Williamsburg, 1943-1945 (Box 80, Folder 10)
    - Winchester, 1945-1946 (Box 80, Folder 11)
- Series III. Graves of Distinguished Virginians Project, 1944-1950 (accession 24806c)
  The Graves of Distinguished Virginians Project series is housed in 5 boxes with oversized material separated and is arranged into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Correspondence and County Files. The series consists of correspondence, lists, maps, newspaper clippings, and reports.
  In October 1944 the Virginia Conservation Commission's Division of History began a "Graves of Distinguished Virginians" Project. Funded by a $2000 appropriation of the General Assembly, the project's goals was to identify and, if necessary, mark such graves. The bulk of the work on this project was between 1946 and 1948.
  - Subseries A: Correspondence, 1944-1950
    This subseries is housed in 3 boxes and one oversize box and is arranged alphabetically by correspondent with some correspondence and topics separated out. The series consists primarily of correspondence between Division of History staff members, Dr. Hamilton J. Eckenrode, Bryan Conrad and J.R.V. Daniel and interested citizens concerning the graves of distinguished Virginians. Topics include: tombstone inscriptions and information on the location of graves.
    - Graves of Distinguished Virginians - Official List for Corrections, Eliminations and (Suggested) Additional Names (Box 81, Folder 1)
    - Graves of Distinguished Virginians - Work List (See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 4) (Box 81, Folder 2)
    - Alphabetical List of Graves of Distinguished Virginians with County locations (2 copies) (Box 81, Folder 3)
    - Grave Inscriptions (Box 81, Folder 4)
    - Proposed Grave Markers (Box 81, Folder 5)
    - Graves - Current Investigation - "Priorities" (Box 81, Folder 6)
    - Alexandria Gazette - Byrd (Box 81, Folder 7)
    - Capron - Cunningham (Box 81, Folder 8)
    - List of Congressmen (2 copies) (Box 81, Folder 9)
    - DAR - Guthrie (Box 81, Folder 10)
    - Graves, L.N., Installation of Markers (Box 81, Folder 11)
    - Grave Markers - Bounds, Paul W. (Granite Markers) (Box 81, Folder 12)
    - Haley - Hutton (Box 82, Folder 1)
    - Harrison (Benjamin's) Material (Box 82, Folder 2)
    - Henwood and Wilson (Granite Markers) (Box 82, Folder 3)
    - Howard, E.H. (Eastern Shore Marker Contract) (Box 82, Folder 4)
    - Ingham - Mullett (Box 82, Folder 5)
    - Mc (Box 82, Folder 6)
    - Marker Order Folder (Box 82, Folder 7)
    - Marker Bids and Orders (Box 82, Folder 8)
    - Miscellaneous Folder (Box 82, Folder 9)
    - Nelson - Nicar (Box 82, Folder 10)
    - National Park Service (Eight Superintendents) (Box 82, Folder 11)
    - Newspaper Clippings (Box 82, Folder 12)
    - Owens - Ryland (Box 82, Folder 13)
    - Saunders - Swem (See Also Oversize Box 2, Folder 6) (Box 83, Folder 1)
    - Suspense Letters (Box 83, Folder 2)
    - Tabb - Tynes (Box 83, Folder 3)
    - Tombstone Inscriptions (Box 83, Folder 4)
    - Upshur - Wright (Box 83, Folder 5)
    - Whitelaw, Ralph T. (Box 83, Folder 6)
    - Wold, Ansel, Washington, DC (Box 83, Folder 7)
    - X-Y-Z (Box 83, Folder 8)
  - Subseries B: County Files
    This subseries is housed in 3 boxes and is arranged alphabetically by locality. The series consists of lists of distinguished Virginians buried in each locality and an approximate location of their grave. A few localities include tombstone inscriptions and newspaper clippings about the project.
    - Accomack County (Box 83, Folder 9)
    - Albemarle County (Box 83, Folder 10)
    - Amelia County (Box 83, Folder 11)
    - Amherst County (Box 83, Folder 12)
    - Appomattox County (Box 83, Folder 13)
    - Arlington County (Box 83, Folder 14)
    - Augusta County (Box 83, Folder 15)
    - Bath County (Box 83, Folder 16)
    - Bland County (Box 83, Folder 17)
    - Botetourt County (Box 83, Folder 18)
    - Brunswick County (Box 83, Folder 19)
    - Buckingham County (Box 83, Folder 20)
    - Campbell County (Box 84, Folder 1)
    - Caroline County (Box 84, Folder 2)
    - Charles City County (Box 84, Folder 3)
    - Charlotte County (Box 84, Folder 4)
    - Chesterfield County (Box 84, Folder 5)
    - Clarke County (Box 84, Folder 6)
    - Culpeper County (Box 84, Folder 7)
    - Cumberland County (Box 84, Folder 8)
    - Dinwiddie County (Box 84, Folder 9)
    - Elizabeth City County (Box 84, Folder 10)
    - Essex County (Box 84, Folder 11)
    - Fairfax County (Box 84, Folder 12)
    - Fauquier County (Box 84, Folder 13)
    - Fluvanna County (Box 84, Folder 14)
    - Franklin County (Box 84, Folder 15)
    - Frederick County (Box 84, Folder 16)
    - Giles County (Box 84, Folder 17)
    - Gloucester County (Box 84, Folder 18)
    - Goochland County (Box 84, Folder 19)
    - Grayson County (Box 84, Folder 20)
    - Halifax County (Box 84, Folder 21)
    - Hanover County (Box 84, Folder 22)
    - Henrico County (Box 84, Folder 23)
    - Henry County (Box 84, Folder 24)
    - Isle of Wight County (Box 84, Folder 25)
    - King and Queen County (Box 84, Folder 26)
    - King George County (Box 84, Folder 27)
    - King William County (Box 84, Folder 28)
    - Lancaster County (Box 84, Folder 29)
    - Lee County (Box 84, Folder 30)
    - Loudoun County (Box 84, Folder 31)
    - Louisa County (Box 84, Folder 32)
    - Lunenburg County (Box 84, Folder 33)
    - Madison County (Box 84, Folder 34)
    - Mathews County (Box 84, Folder 35)
    - Mecklenburg County (Box 84, Folder 36)
    - Middlesex County (Box 84, Folder 37)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 84, Folder 38)
    - Montgomery County (Box 84, Folder 39)
    - Nansemond County (Box 84, Folder 40)
    - Nelson County (Box 84, Folder 41)
    - New Kent County (Box 84, Folder 42)
    - Norfolk County (Box 84, Folder 43)
    - Northampton County (Box 84, Folder 44)
    - Northumberland County (Box 84, Folder 45)
    - Nottoway County (Box 84, Folder 46)
    - Page County (Box 84, Folder 47)
    - Patrick County (Box 84, Folder 48)
    - Pittsylvania County (Box 84, Folder 49)
    - Powhatan County (Box 84, Folder 50)
    - Prince Edward County (Box 84, Folder 51)
    - Prince George County (Box 84, Folder 52)
    - Prince William County (Box 84, Folder 53)
    - Princess Anne County (Box 84, Folder 54)
    - Pulaski County (Box 84, Folder 55)
    - Rappahannock County (Box 84, Folder 56)
    - Richmond County (Box 84, Folder 57)
    - Roanoke County (Box 84, Folder 58)
    - Rockbridge County (Box 84, Folder 59)
    - Rockingham County (Box 84, Folder 60)
    - Russell County (Box 84, Folder 61)
    - Scott County (Box 85, Folder 1)
    - Shenandoah County (Box 85, Folder 2)
    - Smyth County (Box 85, Folder 3)
    - Southampton County (Box 85, Folder 4)
    - Spotsylvania County (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - Stafford County (Box 85, Folder 6)
    - Surry County (Box 85, Folder 7)
    - Sussex County (Box 85, Folder 8)
    - Tazewell County (Box 85, Folder 9)
    - Warren County (Box 85, Folder 10)
    - Warwick County (Box 85, Folder 11)
    - Washington County (Box 85, Folder 12)
    - Westmoreland County (Box 85, Folder 13)
    - West Virginia (Box 85, Folder 14)
    - Wythe County (Box 85, Folder 15)
    - York County (Box 85, Folder 16)
- Series IV. Records, 1929-1950 (accession 25913)
  The Records series is housed in 7 boxes with oversized material separated and is arranged into two subseries. Subseries have been designated for Reference Files and The Hornbook of Virginia History. The series consists of correspondence, minutes, newspapers, newspaper clippings, pamphlets, photographs, postcards and scrapbooks.
  - Subseries A: Reference Files
    This subseries is housed in 4 boxes and two oversize folders and is arranged alphabetically by subject or correspondent. The series consists primarily of topical reference files. Notable subjects include: Bell Tower, Covered Bridges in Virginia (including some photographs and WPA Historical Inventory Forms), Division of History and Archaeology (organization and reports), and George Washington. The material on Washington includes several issues of Clip Sheet, published by the United States George Washington Bicentennial Commission. In addition to the subject files, the subseries also consists of correspondence between Division of History staff members, Dr. Hamilton J. Eckenrode, Bryan Conrad and J.R.V. Daniel and individuals concerning the Division's work. It is unknown why these correspondence were separated from the main Correspondence File (Series I.). Notable correspondents include: W. Edwin Hemphill and Alexander Weddell.
    - Anderson, General James A., Commissioner of Highways (Box 86, Folder 1)
    - A.P.V.A. (The Association for the Preservation of Virginia Antiquities) (Box 86, Folder 2)
    - Archaeology - See also folder for E.B. Sacrey, Secretary, Archaeology Society of Virginia (Box 86, Folder 3)
    - Architecture (drawings) (Box 86, Folder 4)
    - Arnold, George P. (Box 86, Folder 5)
    - Battle, Governor John Stuart (Box 86, Folder 6)
    - Battlefield Markers Association - Battlefield Markers in Richmond Vicinity, List of (Box 86, Folder 7)
    - Battles and Battlefields in Virginia (Lists, etc.) (Box 86, Folder 8)
    - Bell Tower (Capitol Square) (Box 86, Folder 9)
    - Berkeley, Jr., Francis L. (Box 86, Folder 10)
    - Calendar - Old and New Style Explained (Box 86, Folder 11)
    - Capitol Square - Data (Box 86, Folder 12)
    - Cappon, Dr. Lester J. (Highway Historical Marker Advisory Committee) (Box 86, Folder 13)
    - Catechism (Box 86, Folder 14)
    - Church, Randolph W. (State Librarian - 1947) (Box 86, Folder 15)
    - Churches in Virginia (Box 86, Folder 16)
    - Coale, Commander Griffin Baily (Box 86, Folder 17)
    - Covered Bridges in Virginia (Box 86, Folder 18)
    - Daniel, James R.V. (Box 87, Folder 1)
    - Forts (Early Virginia Frontier Forts) (Box 87, Folder 2)
    - Genealogists Working in State Library (Box 87, Folder 3)
    - Governor of Virginia, List of (Box 87, Folder 4)
    - Governor of Virginia - Kibler/Daniel Correspondence (Box 87, Folder 5)
    - Hemphill, Dr. W. Edwin (Box 87, Folder 6)
    - Historic Places (Days and Hours Open to Public) (Box 87, Folder 7)
    - Historical Sketches, 1930-1933 (Box 87, Folder 8)
    - Historical Sketches (Miscellaneous Articles), 1934-1935 (Box 87, Folder 9)
    - Historical Sketches (Miscellaneous Articles), 1936-1937 (Box 87, Folder 10)
    - Historical Sketches of States (for Sesquicentennial) (Box 87, Folder 11)
    - History and Archeaology, Division of (Box 88, Folder 1)
    - Huguenot Society of the Founders of Manakin (Box 88, Folder 2)
    - McCormick, Cyrus H. (Centennial of the Reaper - Material) (Box 88, Folder 3)
    - McDougall, Mrs. John Franklin (Huguenont Society, etc.) (Box 88, Folder 4)
    - Meade, Everard K. (Box 88, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 88, Folder 6)
    - Mountain Peaks in Virginia Above 4000 Feet Elevation (Box 88, Folder 7)
    - Old Families of Virginia, List of (Box 88, Folder 8)
    - Photographs of Monuments, Markers and Gravestones, List of (Box 88, Folder 9)
    - Presidents of the United States and their Wives (Box 88, Folder 10)
    - Rivers in Virginia (Box 88, Folder 11)
    - Roads in Virginia (Colonial) (Box 88, Folder 12)
    - Sacrey, E.B., Secretary, Archeaology Society of Virginia (See Also Archaeology folder) (Box 88, Folder 13)
    - State Bird (Box 88, Folder 14)
    - State Capitol (Box 88, Folder 15)
    - State Flag (Box 88, Folder 16)
    - State Flower (Box 89, Folder 1)
    - State Motto (Box 89, Folder 2)
    - State Poem(s) (Box 89, Folder 3)
    - State Seal (Box 89, Folder 4)
    - State Song (Box 89, Folder 5)
    - State Towns and Cities (Box 89, Folder 6)
    - Surplus Property (Box 89, Folder 7)
    - Torrence, William Clayton (Virginia Historical Society) (Box 89, Folder 8)
    - Tracer File - Highway Department (M.F. Pleasants) (Box 89, Folder 9)
    - George Washington's Barn, Mill and Distillery (Box 89, Folder 10)
    - George Washington Bicentennial (See Also Oversize Box 2, Folders 7 and 8) (Box 89, Folder 11)
    - George Washington's Journeys to Williamsburg (Burgess Road) (Box 89, Folder 12)
    - George Washington Memorial Highway (Box 89, Folder 13)
    - George Washington's Southern Tour, 1791 (Box 89, Folder 14)
    - Weddell, Alexander W., "Virginia House," Richmond, Virginia (Box 89, Folder 15)
    - Werowocomoco - Arthur Gray (Box 89, Folder 16)
    - Whitelaw, Ralph T. (Box 89, Folder 17)
    - Wold, Ansel, Clerk, Washington, DC (Box 89, Folder 18)
    - Yorktown Monument (Box 89, Folder 19)
  - Subseries B: The Hornbook of Virginia History
    This series is housed in 3 boxes and includes information on the publication of The Hornbook of Virginia History by the Virginia Department of Conservation and Development, Division of History in 1949. Notable records include: minutes of the 21 March 1947 meeting of the History Advisory Committee, correspondence, comments and revisions to brief Virginia histories written by Everard Kidder Meade and H.J. Eckenrode, reviews, scrapbook, and requests for copies.
    - Hornbook History Outline, 1947-1949 (part one) (Letters from members of Advisory Committee, annotations, suggestions, re-writes, original and revised copies, etc. - including all such pertaining to Meade's version) (Box 90, Folder 1)
    - Hornbook History Outline, 1947-1949 (part two) (Letters from members of Advisory Committee, annotations, suggestions, re-writes, original and revised copies, etc. - including all such pertaining to Meade's version) (Box 90, Folder 2)
    - Hornbook History Outline, 1947-1948 (part one) (Copies of Eckenrode's "Brief Outline of Virginia History" returned by and showing annotations of various members of the History Advisory Committee) (Box 90, Folder 3)
    - Hornbook History Outline, 1947-1948 (part two) (Copies of Eckenrode's "Brief Outline of Virginia History" returned by and showing annotations of various members of the History Advisory Committee) (Box 90, Folder 4)
    - W. Edwin Hemphill, Drafts and Correspondence, 1947-1949 (Box 90, Folder 5)
    - History Hornbook of Virginia - Samples of Proposed Material (Box 90, Folder 6)
    - Material re Revision of A Brief Outline of Virginia History (Box 91, Folder 1)
    - Hornbook of Virginia History (Complete Office Set) (Box 91, Folder 2)
    - Hornbook - Lewis's Samples (Box 91, Folder 3)
    - Baughman Company (Printing of Hornbook) (Box 91, Folder 4)
    - Hornbook of Virginia History - Errata Sheets (Box 91, Folder 5)
    - Hornbook Clippings, Letters and Reviews (Box 91, Folder 6)
    - The Hornbook Scrapbook (Box 91, Folder 7)
    - Hornbook Labels (Box 91, Folder 8)
    - Special Requests for Hornbook (Box 91, Folder 9)
    - Survey of Virginia Public Schools as to need for A Hornbook of Virginia History (Counties) (Box 91, Folder 10)
    - Survey of Virginia Public Schools as to need for A Hornbook of Virginia History (Cities) (Box 91, Folder 11)
    - Suspense Requests (Hornbook) (Box 92, Folder 1)
    - Unusual and Special Requests (Hornbook) (Box 92, Folder 2)
    - Hornbook - Special Copies to (Box 92, Folder 3)
    - Some "Prize" Letters (Box 92, Folder 4)
    - Hornbook - Inventory and Distribution (Box 92, Folder 5)
    - Extra Copies of Excepts re Hornbook (Box 92, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence re Hornbook Comments and Requests, A-Z (Box 92, Folder 7)
- Series V. Historical Material, 1927-1950 (Accession 41571)
  The Historical Material is housed in 17 boxes with oversized material separated and is arranged alphabetically by county followed by a separate section of newspapers and magazines arranged by sections. City historical material is interfiled with the nearest county. For example City of Richmond material is filed with Henrico County. A 3x5 card files provides a rough topical index to the collection. The series consists of historical sketches, maps, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and photographs.
  Contents include historical data on counties and information on historic sites and places of each interest within each locality. Notable records include two photographs from the Great Dismal Swamp. The first photograph shows gnarled cypress roots in Lake Drummond, near Norfolk (no date); the second, dated 1899, shows the locomobile of John Wallace, Norfolk, the "first motor vehicle other than by electric power" (Norfolk County, Box 103, Folder 1). Other items of interest include: The Spirit of Orange: A Pageant Portraying a Few High Points of Orange County History in Relation to Local, National and International Affairs, 3 May 1930, official program for forty-third annual reunion of Confederate Veterans, in Orange, 16-18 September 1930 (Box 103, Folder 4); Glen Mary: Past and Present by A.V.S. Milbourne, 1935, photograph of commissioners and historians at Skyland, including W.E. Carson and Harry F. Byrd, (Page County, Box 103, Folder 5); newspaper clippings concerning the case of Odell Waller, a Pittsylvania County sharecropper executed for murder on 2 July 1942 (Box 103, Folder 6); photographs of Wanda Hawley, a silent motion picture actress, Helen Wainwright, Olympic swimming and diving champion, and Helen Hentschel, an outboard motor boat racer, at Virginia Beach, Princess Anne County, n.d. (Box 104, Folder 3);and Directory of Surry County, Virginia, 1932-1933 compiled by Gordon C. Berryman (Box 105, Folder 9).
  - Accomack County (Box 93, Folder 1)
  - Albemarle County, A-H (Box 93, Folder 2)
  - Albemarle County, J-W (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Alleghany County (Box 93, Folder 4)
  - Amelia County (Box 93, Folder 5)
  - Amherst County (Box 93, Folder 6)
  - Appomattox County (Box 93, Folder 7)
  - Arlington County (Box 93, Folder 8)
  - Augusta County (Box 93, Folder 9)
  - Bath County (Box 94, Folder 1)
  - Bedford County (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Bland County (Box 94, Folder 3)
  - Botetourt County (Box 94, Folder 4)
  - Brunswick County (Box 94, Folder 5)
  - Buchanan County (Box 94, Folder 6)
  - Buckingham County (Box 94, Folder 7)
  - Campbell County (Box 94, Folder 8)
  - Caroline County (Box 94, Folder 9)
  - Charles City County (Box 94, Folder 10)
  - Charles City County (Information on Old Homes photographed by History Division), Berkley-Indian Fields (Box 94, Folder 11)
  - Charles City County (Information on Old Homes photographed by History Division), Kittiwan-Wilcox Wharf (Box 95, Folder 1)
  - Charlotte County (Box 95, Folder 2)
  - Clarke County (Box 95, Folder 3)
  - Culpeper County (Box 95, Folder 4)
  - Cumberland County (Box 95, Folder 5)
  - Dickenson County (Box 95, Folder 6)
  - Dinwiddie County (Box 95, Folder 7)
  - Dinwiddie County (Petersburg) (Box 95, Folder 8)
  - Elizabeth City County (Box 95, Folder 9)
  - Essex County (Box 96, Folder 1)
  - Fairfax County (Box 96, Folder 2)
  - Fairfax County (Alexandria) (Box 96, Folder 3)
  - Fauquier County (Box 96, Folder 4)
  - Fluvanna County (Box 96, Folder 5)
  - Franklin County (Box 96, Folder 6)
  - Frederick County (Box 96, Folder 7)
  - Giles County (Box 96, Folder 8)
  - Gloucester County (Box 96, Folder 9)
  - Goochland County (Box 96, Folder 10)
  - Grayson County (Box 97, Folder 1)
  - Greene County (Box 97, Folder 2)
  - Greensville County (Box 97, Folder 3)
  - Hanover County (Information on Old Homes photographed by History Division), A-O (Box 97, Folder 4)
  - Hanover County (Information on Old Homes photographed by History Division), P-W (Box 97, Folder 5)
  - Hanover County (Box 97, Folder 6)
  - Hanover County (newspaper and Randolph-Macon Papers) (Box 97, Folder 7)
  - Henrico County (Box 97, Folder 8)
  - Henrico County (Richmond City - General Folder) (part one) (Box 97, Folder 9)
  - Henrico County (Richmond City - General Folder) (part two) (Box 97, Folder 10)